Okay, so you've had your first attempt at writing code and fixing errors.
好，你首次嘗試編碼 與修正錯誤
This type of experimentation is a critical part of learning
這是學習很重要的部分
Android development.
Android開發
Let's talk about the size of views now.
讓我們談談檢視大小
We know that the width and height are expressed in DP values, or
我們知道寬與高 是以DP值呈現
density independent pixels.
密度獨立像素
This makes it look good across a range of different devices.
這在不同裝置看起來都很棒
However, there's still room for improvement in this UI.
但還是有空間可以改善UI
If I change this text here to be something longer, for example wait,
若我把這裡的文字變長 舉例來說，等等
today's your birthday?
今天是你的生日？
Notice the text updates here, but it wraps to two lines.
看到這裡的文字更新 但變成兩行
Ideally it would all be on one line,
都在一行是理想的
because there is plenty of screen real estate on this side.
因為這一邊有很多螢幕空間
The reason the box didn't change sides,
格子沒有換邊的原因
is because we gave it a fixed width and height of 150dp.
因為我們把寬與高固定在150dp
When you set a very specific value for
當你設定很特定的值
width and height like this, this is called hard coding a value.
像這樣的寬與高 這是固定編碼值
It's generally considered not a good practice,
這不是一個好的練習
because if the text ever changes like this, then it looks funny.
因為若文字這樣改變 看起來會很好笑
We have to go and change the width to something like 200, so
我們要把寬度改成200
that it fits all on one line.
就可以在一行
But it would be such a hassle to keep updating the width and
但一直根據文字
height, based on what the text is.
更新寬與高很討厭
You might not know what the text is until later.
你可能不知道之後的文字
For example, if you have an app that's showing news articles,
舉例來說 有個顯示新文章的軟體
the title of each story may change.
每個故事標題可能改變
And you don't want your UI to break, if you have a really long title or
你不希望UI分行 若標題真的很長
if you have a really short title.
或標題很短
So in Android we can solve this problem by setting the width
在Android裡面 我們可以設定特別的
to be a special value called wrap content.
寬值來解決，叫包含內文
This address, the width of the TextView, so
這處理TextView的寬度
that it's precisely the width of the content inside of it.
這是內文的準確寬度
It's not too short and it's not too large.
不會太短也不會太長
It's just right.
剛剛好
Similarly for height instead of setting it to 150 dp, we
高度也一樣 不設定在150dp
can set it to the special value of wrap content, then the text view will update,
我們可以設定包含內文 特別的值，文字檢視就會更新
so that the size of the text use only as tall as the text inside of it.
使用的文字大小 就會跟內文一樣高
Now, setting wrap content for height and width is very powerful, because you
現在，設定包含內文的 寬高很有用
might have content decided on the right here, which will now be shifted over,
因為你這裡可能會有內文 現在會改變到這裡
because you don't have this excess space in the text view.
因為你沒有多餘的文字檢視空間
And similarly, if you have other text views below this,
同樣地 若其他文字檢視在這之下
now they can shift up to right below this first text view.
他們可以往上調到 第一個文字檢視下
Back to the news app example, if this was the story title, you wouldn't
回到新聞軟體範例 若這是故事標題，你不會
want the story description to be all the way down here, 150 DPIs away.
希望故事一直往下到這裡 150DPIs
Instead, you'd want the description to be right up under the story title.
但是你不要說明 直接在標題下面
Zooming back out, let's try a shorter string.
縮小一點，試試看短的字串
Okay, it's time for you to practice now.
好，現在換你練習
We want you to change a couple things with the code.
我們要你修改一些編碼
Change the width and the height of the TextView to wrap content.
改變TextView的 寬高到包含內文
Then change the text to be a really long, long sentence, or paragraph, so
然後把文字變成 非常長的句子或段落
that it displays more than one line of text on the device preview.
在裝置預覽顯示多行文字
You can even type out the full birthday song if you wanted, that's pretty long.
你也可以輸入整首生日快樂歌 那滿長的
The code to get you started is linked below.
開始進行的編碼連結在下面